Erick Latshaw

South Yarmouth, MA | (774)-212-5937 | erickjlatshaw@gmail.com | Linkedin | Github | Portfolio

Junior Game Programmer

SUMMARY

I am a passionate programmer and game developer with abilities in both 2D and 3D game creation. I have experience working in game jams as well as larger team projects. I am incredibly comfortable with version control and I pride myself in my clean code and game architecture with an emphasis on making designer-friendly, decoupled systems.

- Developed dozens of game systems to make the implementation of new mechanics seamless
- Designed and developed at least six titles, with two in the process of being shipped late 2022 where I served as lead engineer.
- 4 years game development experience and 7 years software development experience.

SKILLS

Git, Unity, Unreal Engine, Godot, C#, C++, GDScript, Java, Python, MySQL, OOP, Agile, Scrum

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

Marist College, Poughkeepsie, NY | TA for Game Deisng and Programming I

- Taught a group of 20 highschool students Godot over an intensive 3-week period
- Created Syllabus and lesson plans
- Instilled Game design patterns, clean code principles, and data structures

SEPTEMBER 2018 - MARCH 2020

Marist College, Poughkeepsie, NY | Student Data Analyst

- Worked to enhance and train a model to predict the grade of students in order to identify at-risk individuals so they could be aided.
- Gained real-world experience in data science
- Group project experience both virtual and in-person
- Regular use of MySQL, Python, and Git
- Helped migrate databases from Netezza to MariaDB server

EDUCATION

August 2018 - May 2022

Marist College, Poughkeepsie, NY

BS, Games & Emerging Media - Technical Concentration